Okay so now we're going to start on the darkest dark, large areas of colour.
Let's mix up a touch of turps on my brush, take some black, take some dark
alizarin, some black to make it slightly deeper, a white palette,
you can see how warm that is and show through. Okay so a bit of a vignette with all this, oops
okay that's vignette. Okay then we've got this shadow, that shadow looks like something around
violet, touch of burnt umber, black in there, a bit of turps, comes up around there,
taking that up to the edge so I don't want any halos. Okay then you've got the transition,
the use of the brush, using around size five sixes, make something slightly lighter,
okay maybe take some of this, mid, mid to dark, touch of burnt umber, touch of black in there,
test it, test this, maybe a bit too violet, touch this green, take that down, neutralise it,
something around that, just lighten this a bit so you can see. I'm going to soften that edge using
the blunt side of the brush, come back into that shape with the violet. Okay now we're going to
look for the, similar kind of mix to the um the darin, violet, purple, touch of turps, a bit more
playable, take some of this green, okay check that, got much room between the other hair,
the canvas, something around there, okay make a darker version, that's pretty light,
so this is probably a bit lighter, make a darker version around here, I'm going to get,
use another brush, I'm going to make a darker version of that, more green, of turps in there,
green, some white, too dark, maybe too dark, turps, corner of the brush, putting in a test,
touch more purple, a bit deeper, okay so you could say something around that,
I'm going to put this colour in, so I'm going off the, you can see there how dark it is in reality,
I'm not quite the same as the photo shot, just putting that in, that looks okay,
now I'm just working up to these edges, working over the edge and now come back up
on myself, okay I'm going to come around, just lighten some, actually I've got that dark on the
brush, come around the back of the hair, here, look round, so I'm taking this lighter tone,
bring up around the hairline, and then you get a bit lighter, around the back of the hairline,
let's fix a lighter version, slightly lighter, just finish off this, okay so it's just done a
bit more white, a bunch of turps, a bit more, okay just going to bring back the drawing,
okay now we can think about the, actually it's quite dark, just to run the neck, just in here,
start with the shadows now, that's going to be full black with the alizarin,
okay so it's got this kind of turtleneck sweater on, okay then look at the, into the inside of the joe,
that's going to be a bit warmer, kind of burnt umber, maybe some violet
in there, burnt umber violet, right kind of warm, just put that in, this in is one,
maybe a touch of turps, to get that to work that painting, so probably have to go darker in this,
just a bit lighter than a minute, show you how, there's probably something around,
a bit closer to that, a bit of black in there, really to soften it, put that paint down,
looking at the hair, something similar, there's quite a lot of um,
I'm just going to add some more black into that, burnt umber, burnt umber purple black,
a bunch of turps, slightly cooler, so yeah a bit more black in there, okay, okay so this um,
okay then around here you get a slight lighter, so just going to look at the back of the,
the hair, okay so what I'm going to use for that,
probably some violet, some yellow, violet green, color of violet green,
maybe a touch of yellow in there, see if that works, okay maybe um, burnt umber,
some green, burnt umber green, maybe a touch of black, okay something like that,
see um, lighter shape, then say some black, okay so let's say burnt umber and black,
this shape here, okay then got this around here, okay so with that burnt umber black,
a bit of a flick there, slightly darker accent there, okay so I'm going to um,
you can come back in, the background there, shape that a bit, okay so I'm going to call that,
that hair shape at the back, just going to flatten this stuff in here to the tone,
now looking with this tone here, it's going to be slightly um, lighter, a bit warmer,
so more on the um, purple side, so again this is going to probably be around the um, purple,
just the purple burnt umber without the black, a touch of turps in there,
but I'm just observing these shapes, let's look at how it's going to soften,
I'm going to take some of this hair into the background and go backwards and forwards,
yeah you can go backwards and forwards all this, so I'm going to put something in for
this shape here, so that's going to be, got some yellow in there, got some violet,
some green, maybe yellow and some violet in there, it's a bit closer,
you just put all this, all that in is one, there it goes into the background over here,
and how this hair going in, getting too, over that minute, pull that down,
you can see what's happening, the hair where it gets slightly lighter,
it's probably some yellow burnt umber, say a touch of mid violet in there,
maybe that's too light, maybe that's slightly darker, darker violet in there, checking that,
a bit more yellow, I'm going to make it a bit warmer, more yellow, more violet,
just bring that burnt umber, it kind of comes in more there, it gets a bit darker,
put more on the burnt umber, okay, coming back in, these shapes, yeah just pull the paint down,
okay, it's looking at violet in that, okay, bring those shapes in there, it's looking at the back
of the hair, it's not burnt umber brown, burnt umber brown, sorry, violet, burnt umber,
purple, purple burnt umber, so it's your basic, larger is the color, darkest darks,
okay, so that's the um, darkest darks, larger is the color, okay.